#### **Devin Halladay**

Multidisciplinary designer 440-409-2114 devin@devinhalladay.com

#### INTRODUCTION

My name is Devin Halladay, and I'm a designer with an affinity for product design, user experience, typography, and branding and identity. I thrive in highly concept-driven and fast-paced environments that where norms are frequently challenged.

I live and work according to four core tenets: learn the rules, break them with spirit and intent, experiment relentlessly, and create intelligently.

#### **SELECTED WORKS & WRITING**

Portfolio & Writing: devinhalladay.com Dribbble: dribbble.com/devinhalladay Github: github.com/devinhalladay Behance: behance.com/devinhalladay

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's of Fine Arts Candidate in Graphic Design and Interdisciplinary Sculpture, Maryland Institute College of Art, Expected Graduation May 2019

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Product Designer, Cents 2016-Present

As product design lead at Cents, a funded early-stage financial tech startup, I am in charge of prototyping, visual design, close collaboration with our backend and iOS developer team, user experience, and user research. The Cents iOS app is scheduled to be released in late spring 2017.

## Designer, Freelance 2012-Present

Working with a wide range of clients on projects including product and web design, branding and identity, poster design, and editorial design has allowed me to explore the design landscape freely. I collaborate with developers, designers, and business owners to create highly effective and conceptual solutions for clients in numerous industries, and primarily in the tech and design industries themselves.

## Developer/Open Source Maintainer, Spotio 2016

I reverse engineered and created a theme system for Spotify's desktop apps. Spotio has a large global usersbase and was featured on The Verge, Engadget, and The Next Web.

## Designer, Ministry of Print 2014–2016

An experimental and successful side project, this was a moniker for my poster design practice, which revolved around the relationship between essence and existence, concept and form. Experimentations in communication and representation allowed me to freely break my own rules and discover unexpected ideas through a process of conceptual ideation.

### **EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

## Designer, Leapwise 2014-2015

At Leapwise my job was to create a wide range of designs for clients, ranging from nonprofits to startups to corporations. I worked closely with a team of three other designers and a developer to create effective solutions to client briefs. Additionally, I collaborated daily with the team of developers at Veritix, a Cleveland-based ticketing solutions company, to design and execute a line of ticketing apps and a conceptual rebrand of the company itself and its flagship product, FlashSeats.

### **LEADERSHIP**

2015

# Graphic Design Representative, MICA Student Voice Association 2016–Present

As a departmental representative in MICA's SVA, my job is to collect and organize feedback on the department from my peers and plan actionable steps to improve the graphic design department at MICA. Recently, I began a large restructure of the critique culture and process in the graphic design department at MICA.

## Leader, MICA Design League 2015-Present

I am one of five equal leaders of the MICA Design League, a student-run organization backed by the GD department. MDL sponsors and organizes exhibitions, events, and programming for the department. Responsibilities include organizing meetings and events, meeting with advisors, and leading trips.

# SCHOLARSHIPS, EXHIBITIONS & PUBLICATIONS

2016	Piece featured in the MICA Photography department's juried exhibition <i>Photography: The Form.</i>
2016	Two pieces featured in the MICA Graphic Design Department's exhibition <i>System, Process, Context</i> in the Bronze Gallery.
2016	Spotio, my open-source Rdio-inspired theme for Spotify, featured by <i>The Verge</i> , <i>Engadget</i> , <i>The Next Web</i> , and international tech reporting websites.
2016	Two pieces selected to be featured in I Invited Britney Spears To Dinner (The Invitation Was Not Accepted), a multidisciplinary graphic design exhibition.
2016	Recipient of the Louise N. Myerberg Family Competitive Scholarship.
2016	Two magazines selected by jury to be featured in <i>MICA</i> 's <i>Fall Foundation Show</i> in the fall of 2016.
2016	Featured as an outstanding underclassman in MICA's quarterly magazine, <i>Juxtapositions</i> .
2016	Synesthesia poster featured in MICA Design League's Shhhow!, an exhibition in MICA's Brown Center.

Recipient of MICA scholarships including the Trustee

Scholarship, Fanny B Thalheimer Scholarship, and

Creative Vision Award.